何か用か？
The tycoon, Mr. Battera.
明日　旅立つそうね。
Objective?
選挙も息子さんも放りっ放し？
That would be Greed Island, of course.
あのハゲ！ 何で　こいつに話すかな。
Why are you so interested in a game?
最後まで見届けたら？
You've spent a considerable
amount on it by now.
もう決まっただろ？
It is an expression of love.
俺は十分　楽しんだしな。 レオリオってやつに会えたのが 一番の収穫だ。
Isn't wanting to monopolize
that which you love natural?
あれは　伸び代　デケェぞ。
What is this love you mention?
何言ってるの？
There are many rumors flying around.
４人に絞られただけで 何も決まってないでしょ。
Any comments?
分かってんじゃねえか 俺は　そのこと言ってんの！
I will get my hands on the clue Ging left!
今日の投票は 一応　お前に入れるよ。 お疲れさん。
What time is it?
だから　一体　何言ってるの？ バカ？
Kurapika! It's 2:00 PM.
決まらねえのが決まった って言ってんだよ！
I slept for half a day?
何日まで決まらねえか 知りたいか？ 何で　そんなことが？
It's been two whole days, Kurapika...
おめぇもミザイも 勝つためにやってるからだよ。
Where's the boss? What about the underground auction?
だけど　本当に勝ちたかったら
It ended up being canceled.
もっと早く 必死に勝負すべきだったな。
The rest of the merchandise
will be auctioned online.
どんな汚いてを使っても 投票率をクリアして
The boss accepted that. You're lying.
過半数を取るべきだったんだ。
Eh?
今更　そんなこと 結果論で　どうとでも言えるし。
She was looking forward to
taking part in the auction.
先に言ったら　意地でも 言う通りにしねえだろうが！
I don't see her accepting that so easily...
ホント　面倒くせぇな　てめぇは。
Squala was killed.
まっ 結果論だと思うのは勝手だよ。 Ｘデーまで　そのまんま思ってろ。
And Eliza was inconsolable...
待ってよ！ 何だよ！
The Scarlet Eyes we won were stolen.
ハァ…。 言う通りにするわよ どうすればいいの？
But apparently, the boss was severely shocked by Eliza's state.
何　その 「やれやれ」みたいな感じ。
That was when she said
she wanted to go home.
パリストンが 何考えてるか分からない。
I see. What about Gon and Killua?
どうしたら　あいつに勝てるの？
They're both fine.
俺が　こうしろって言って おめぇが
Around now... He fell asleep.
取りあえず　じゃ 「パリストンが何を考えてるか」 から行こうか？
They're doing what they need to do, so you should get plenty of rest.
負けようとも思っていない。
Our next item
だから　強いんだ。 そんな…　そんなことって…！
is the legendary game, Greed Island !
「勝つぞっていう強い意志があって 人は強くなる」　だろ？ 間違いじゃねえよ　正解だ。
Let's take a look at the mysterious
power this game contains.
ゲーム？ ほら　お前　今 不謹慎だって思っただろ？
As you can see, there is a mysterious power
怒るべきってな。 モラリスト　かつ　バランス重視の マニュアリストだ。 フン！ こっち向け　こら！
that protects the console from any damage, as long as someone is playing inside.
全然　イヌのキャラ 固まってねえじゃん。
This man is Jeitsari.
素のお前じゃん。
He is a player who's inside
the game at this moment.
パリストンにしてみりゃ どっちのお前も知ってるから 分かってんだよ。
In fact, he's the one who signed a contract
次　どう動くか どう考えてるかなんて
allowing us to auction it off.
手に取るようにな。
So this copy wasn't brought here by Ging.
分かった上で勝とうと 思ってないんだ　最強だろ？
Jeitsari left behind the following agreement:
だから！
"If we cannot clear this game
ああしろ　こうしろって 言ったら　お前 絶対　聞かねえだろうが。 何回やんだ？　このやりとり。
before the date specified in the contract, seven active players, including myself, will present seven copies
of the game and console
まず　今回の選挙で お前とパリストンが残る。
to the Southern Piece Auction,
so our talented young Hunters
次のタイマン選挙で １位と２位が逆転する。 そして　それが　ずっと続くだろう。
can clear the game and fulfill our dream." Unfortunately, when we
obtained these copies, two already displayed game over screens.
恐らくパリストンは 投票率を下げに来る。
That means the players also died in real life.
あいつが完全に意思を掌握してる 「協専」の連中が棄権する。
This dangerous game requires
that you risk your own life!
何で？
Make sure you're prepared before you bid.
言ったろ　あいつは 勝つ気も負ける気もない。 Ｘデーまで　のらりくらりさ。
Let's start the bidding at 900 million Jenny!
あいつは　ただ楽しみたいんだ 俺やネテロと一緒だよ。
I have 1 billion! I have 1.5 billion! #105 doubles it to 3 billion.
まっ　俺は　飽きっぽいけどな。
#71 doubles it again... to 6 billion!
あいつは　根気強いぜ。
Hey! That's my brother!
今　残ってる４人で ネテロの意志を継いでるのは
So you indicate how much
you're bidding with your hand?
パリストンだけだ。
Yeah, the auctioneer is able to
instantly discern the highest bid.
あんたに そんなこと言われたくない！
#16 doubles it again... to 12 billion!
そんなに あのエロジジイ　好きか？
#201 doubles it again, to 24 billion! You idiot!
あなたは　Ｘデーが　いつか 教えればいいのです！
Whew, that was close...
根無し草のバカが！
I'm guessing he wasn't able to
decipher that memory card.
まっ　いいけど。
#71 bids 25.5 billion...
次までにキャラ固めしとけ 絡みづれぇし。
How much money does he have?
ネテロが自爆した日
#16 goes all the way up to 30.5 billion!
ハンター協会所有の 大型飛行船が１００機 東ゴルトーに向かった。
Damn it!
記録は残っていない。 表向きは 一斉整備で　格納庫の中って
30.5 billion, huh?
知らなかったろ？
No matter...
整備士か飛行士とは 仲良くしといたほうがいいぞ。
If we can clear this game.
何の話　してるの？
Um, we're Hunters.
それで 約５０００個の繭を回収している。
We're willing to help clear Greed Island.
キメラに配合された半獣人の繭だ。
Don't joke around. Go on home.
全員　念能力を持ってる。
We're not joking! I'm a pro Hunter.
恐らく　もう 全部　孵化してるだろう。
What nonsense. Do you have a license? Yes!
パリストンは こいつらで遊ぼうとしてる。
Uh, you don't. It's at the pawn shop.
デカい庭も手に入れたしな。
Oh. Uh, it's not on me...
Ｘデーは　次のハンター試験日。
See... He's lying. I'm not lying!
ただし 「ハンター十ヶ条」の解釈次第で
Hold on...
少し状況が変わる。
The fact that you're here means
you're certainly not ordinary.
あとは自分で考えろや。 ハンターだろ？
However, I can't blindly
accept everything you say.
え　では　これより 第８回 １３代会長総選挙を行います。
I am indeed looking to hire
Hunters in order to clear this game, but I cannot hire you at this time.
本日の流れですが
Because there can only be so many players.
まず　残りました４名の主張を 聞いていただきまして
Crap... Has our plan failed?
立候補者への質疑応答の後 投票していただく予定です。
I'm thinking that we don't
need to buy the game. We just want the data inside it.
あ　俺のせいか。
And I bet some of the people
who win copies of Greed Island will be looking for players, too.
残念ながら落選してしまった 候補者のコメントです。
There can only be so many players? Each memory card only has the
capacity to store one player's data.
[TV] 私を支持してくれた諸君に まず　礼を言う　ありがとう。
With multitaps, you can have a
maximum of eight players per console.
そして　可能ならば 私を信じて投じてくれた１票を
Oh, right. That Greed Island save used up
次はチードルに 託してくれることを期待する。
all thirty blocks on that memory card. Yeah.
「十二支ん」は 決して一枚岩ではない。
How did you know that?! We have a Greed Island save file.
しかし　その中でも 目指す方角が近い者は存在する。
Have you played the game before?
私の場合　それがチードルだ。
No, we only have a memory card.
彼女の卓越したバランス感覚は
Does that mean...
きっと　協会をいい方向へと 導いてくれるだろう。
If that memory card is real, you would need another item to remove the card
それでは　これより 候補者の主張演説に入りますが
It appears that they are worthy of consideration.
１つだけ　注意点がございます。
I assume that you can use Nen.
本日お集まりの 皆様におかれましては
Show me your Ren. Sure!
へぇ。
It's hopeless. Letting them play would be a waste of time.
ん…。
They'd run around in circles until they died.
中に人は？
We don't need people who'll
drag out the inevitable.
ツボネとカナリアのみだ。
As long as a player is alive inside the game, you can't reset or remove the memory card.
アルカ様は？
They've given up on returning to the real world, choosing to live inside the game.
まだ寝てる 自分から起きるまで待とう。
That is why I must be careful
when selecting players.
もうすぐだ　すぐだぞ　ゴン！
for returning to the real world. And you're saying we aren't strong enough?
万が一　同点票が 続くこともありましょうが
Screening? You're screening players? Yes, the screening will be
on the auction's final day.
あらゆる必需品を 準備しております故 安心して　何回でも何時間でも 何日でも投票してくださいませ。
If you're interested in participating, you'll need to work on your Nen. We were going to do that anyway!
繰り返し　申し上げます。
Let's go, Killua!
１３代会長が決まるまで この会議場から出られません！
Before you go, kid... How did you come by a memory card? I'm not telling you!
それでは　獲得投票数４位の ミザイストムさんから 主張演説をお願いいたします。
Damn it... I'm mad now. We absolutely must pass their screening!
最も会長に　ふさわしいのは
We're bandits.
チードルだと　俺は思う。
We steal.
俺自身は トリプルハンターを目指したい。
A memory card is already inserted, so only one more can play.
この選挙を今日 この回で終わらせるためにも
We can use a multitap. Four more can play now.
俺の意志を尊重してくれると ありがたい。
Nice... So who goes first?
以上だ。
I'll go first.
それでは前回得票数　第３位 チードルさん　どうぞ。
Whoa... He really did disappear. I was kind of skeptical...
私も簡潔に言いますね。
What was that?
聴衆の皆さん　私は１３代会長に
It's a game. Wanna play? I'll pass. If I feel like it.
レオリオ氏を強く推薦します。
Okay. Catch you later, then.
以上です。
He disappeared, too. What kind of game is this?
一体　何考えてんだ？ チードル
A game where you can actually die.
…っていうか そもそも選ばれたくねえし
It's listed in the auction catalog.
でも　言いたいことは 言っとくか
I'm so mad!
何しろ　俺は 選挙どころじゃねえし
I can't believe how he spouted off! Damn it!
えっと ありがとうございました。
Still, he's right.
それでは　続きまして 前回２位のレオリオさん　どうぞ。
What do you mean? Chill out a little.
笑顔が消えたわよ パリストン
We should start thinking about
taking this to the next level. Next level?
あんたの思い通りになんか 絶対させない
Hatsu. You know, our special abilities.
あら？　レオリオさん？
Kurapika started learning Nen when we did.
お願いいたします　どうぞ。 レオリオさん。
But he was able to fight the Troupe because of his special abilities.
レオリオ　こら！
Yeah, Kurapika obtained powers that
寝てんのか　てめぇは！ しばき回すぞ　クソガキ！
make him basically invincible against the Troupe
あっ！　俺？
by placing his life on the line. We can't follow his example.
ダメだ　頭まとまんねえ ホント　何やってんだ　俺
We need abilities without
too much or too little risk, which still fit our specialties. Something practical and effective...
もういいや　取りあえず…
That's what we have to come up with.
あ　言いたいことだけ 言わせてもらうぜ。
Well, I knew this would happen. Let's take this one step at a time.
俺が会長になったら　協会を
First, what kind of abilities do you want?
私物化するからな！
What kind of abilities do I want?
最初に お前ら全員に出す命令は
You must have at least a vague idea.
「ゴンを助けるため すぐに動け！」だ
Uh, a really strong power! That's too vague! Start by thinking within your own category.
俺はな　こんなことしてる 場合じゃねえんだよ。
You're an Enhancer, so think of a power that strengthens something.
ゴンのため 何もしてやれてねえんだがよ。
Then we ask, what part of you do you
want to strengthen, and how?
あいつは… ゴンは今　死にかけてる。
That hurt! What about you, then? I already know what I want.
仲間なのに　友達なのに…。
That's why I'm helping you.
それを知ったのは　つい最近だ。
Really? What do you want? It's a secret. Huh?
あいつは　俺が
Gon, I'm going to go start
practicing my special ability.
自分のため勉強して 酒飲んで　部屋替えて
You keep thinking about it. Though it's possible that I'm the only
one who'll pass the screening.
ズリセンこいて　女連れ込んで ネットしてる間中　ずっと…。
He'll just get distracted
前会長と仲間達と一緒に。 その中の１人は ゴンを助けるため
unless I give him a scare. Visualize my aura fusing with electricity.
俺は　ゴンに声を掛けることしか できなかった。
Then I visualize
声を掛け続けることしかできねえ。
the electricity being released,
while refining my Nen!
とにかく考えろ！ 思い付いたら動け！
Damn it! I'll make him eat those words!
俺にできることがあるなら言え！ 何でもやる！
You sound determined, Gon. Kurapika! Are you better? Yeah, my fever broke.
ジン
He doesn't look fine.
なぜ　あなたが　あの時 よけなかったかが分かった
But if Kurapika finds out that the spiders are still in Yorknew City...
「こいつなら もしかしたら」って
Is there any way to stop him?
すでに　あの瞬間　思ったのね
So how did the auction go?
いいわ　彼が会長で
I believe you were after an expensive game? Oh, yeah... Tea
クソっ　何か言わなくて いいことまで言っちまった。
I see. So they're screening players...
ズリセンは忘れてくれ　以上。
Say, what kind of training did you do?
私達がサポートすれば
Once I decided to conjure chains, I did a lot of image training... I closed my eyes, while feeling real chains.
彼は　きっと　いい会長になる
I drew hundreds, thousands of sketches. I looked at chains, licked chains...
I also smelled and listened to chains.
それでは最後に　前回１位の パリストンさん　どうぞ。
My master told me to do nothing
but handle chains all the time. After a while, he took them away. That was when I began to hallucinate chains...
もう無理よ　パリストン あなたが これから何を話そうが 私の８７票と
Eventually, those hallucinations
began to feel heavy and cold, and I could hear them grating.
ミザイの７２票 そして　５７の浮動票も
Once I reached that point,
I was able to conjure chains.
レオリオの９５票に加わるわ
Other than that, I did the same training as you. Ten and Ren.
その総数　３１１票
I know, Kurapika...
得票率は　５０％を超える
You can be my master!
１３代会長は　レオリオよ
You can point out what I'm doing right.
皆様　静粛にお願いいたします。
This way, I can keep Kurapika occupied
while the auction takes place.
ケータイでの通話は ご遠慮ください。
I'm sorry, but I cannot.
えっと　そろそろ デカい声　出しますよ。
Huh? My boss will be leaving tomorrow. I am obligated to accompany her.
皆さん　そのまま 電話してもらってて結構です。
You're leaving Yorknew City? Yeah.
これこそハンター魂だと 僕は言いたい！
I'm still concerned about the spiders...
ゴン君を救うため 僕も　この選挙が終わり次第 尽力することを約束します。
But it's been two days, so they're probably already gone.
しかしながら　そのことと選挙とは 切り離して考えねばなりません。
Yeah, that's a good idea. Who taught you Nen?
４人の中で最も会長に ふさわしいのは
You should probably ask them rather than me.
僕が３年間
I can tell you right now
ネテロ会長の下で副会長を務めて 分かったことがあります。
that Enhancers don't need special abilities. Why not?
それは　会長に必要な ３つの条件です。
Because Enhancers are the most balanced between offense and defense.
１つは　戦闘力。 これは　我々の活動の性質上 絶対条件。
If you master Ten and Ren, those will be strong enough to be
considered special abilities.
今回の件でも明らかですよね。
But I don't have time.
２つ目は　経験。
I have to pass a screening in four days...
知恵は経験により高まります。 ハンター歴は 長いに越したことはないんです。
Gon-kun, if I were a judge, I would be disappointed to see
an improvised special ability.
何で…　何で　こいつが話すと こんなに感情が逆立つのだろう
Listen carefully, Gon-kun. You must not emulate that Kurapika person.
こいつが全く本心を さらけ出していないことが
You needn't emulate anyone else
「この人が会長だったら 協会は　まず大丈夫だ！」と
when you're already so strong. You think so? Of course.
皆さんが思える人物は そうそういるものではありません。
Reflect on the things you've been able to do.
チードルさんには　武力が レオリオさんには　経験が…。
That should help you find the answer you seek.
そして　僕には　全部足りません。
A-A hint...
はい　ここ　笑うとこですよ。
Please give me a hint! You sound pretty flustered...
何が狙いか それを考えるのよ
Haste makes waste. In the end, hard work always pays off.
全てを兼ね備えているのは
I would agree if it weren't for this deadline...
壇上には　ミザイストムさんしか いないと　僕は思います。
All right, here's a big hint, then.
パリストン支持の ２９０票のうち １２０票くらいは 「協専」のハンター
You only showed that Tsezgerra
person your normal Ren, right? Yeah.
そして　審査部をはじめ
Next time, show him everything simultaneously.
パリストンが統括している 事務執行部のスタッフが３０票
Everything? Yes, listen carefully.
恐らくパリストンは サインを送って
Show him everything you've
learned simultaneously.
それでは　これより 候補者同士の質疑応答に入ります。
Everything I've learned simultaneously.
今のパリストンの演説で レオリオに全て流れるはずだった 浮動票は　少し割れる
Ten... Shroud myself in aura. Zetsu...
恐らく　こんな具合に
Suppress my aura.
でも　それは結論が もう一回　先に延びただけで
Ren... Bring forth an incredible amount of aura.
こちらの狙いと変わらない
And Hatsu...
この質疑応答で
Wait.
何かが変わる？
Ren requires me to bring forth aura, while Zetsu requires suppressing it.
いいわよ！ 自分で考えるわよ！
Oh? His brain fried again?
じゃ　僕からいいですか？
Hang in there, Gon.
いや　まず俺だ。 まず　さっきも言ったように 俺は会長をやる気はない。
If you take too long, I'll leave you behind!
いいえ。
It's impossible...
先ほどは　やりたくないわけじゃ ないと　おっしゃってました。
How do I bring forth and suppress
something at the same time?
ただね　ミザイさん本人の 意思ではないんです。 えっ？ みんなの意思なんです 大事なのは。
Reflect on the things you've been able to do.
やるべき人は　やらざるを得ない 状況になるんです。 それが器なんですよ。 もう　自分が　どうだからとか やめましょうよ。
After Wing-san helped unleash my Nen, I went into battle knowing only Ten, and got myself seriously hurt.
小細工をやめて 皆さんの意思に任せるんです。
But in the process, I mastered Zetsu. Then I learned Gyo to see through
Hisoka's special ability.
でも　何で　こんなに ミザイを推すの？
Gyo? Right! I have Gyo!
まさか私達が これで欲を出して
Gyo... Concentrate aura in your eyes
レオリオじゃ　なく　ミザイを２位に 押し上げるとでも思ってるの？
to see hidden aura.
なぜなら　レオリオの票は 基本　浮動票 レオリオが脱落すれば
Right, I concentrated on my eyes, so I never noticed what else was happening.
その票は パリストンにも流れかねない
There's a little aura being released.
でも　もし　レオリオが残れば 票を統制している私と
If I can suppress it, I'll be doing everything at once!
モラウ票は 完全な反パリストン票
Yes! I did it!
つまり　パリストンには １票も行かない
No good...
分かった？　ミザイ ああ　分かってるよ
The second I relaxed, it fell apart.
確実にパリストンを落とせれば それが一番だ クライムハンターの 俺の勘がいっている 証拠はない
But it works! If I can concentrate the aura
from my Ren in one place, that'll be a lot of power.
本人は　全く手を下していない 可能性はある
I want to test that power!
しかし　確実に こいつは闇側の人間
Gon-kun, haste makes waste. Osu!
絶対に　これ以上　協会内部で 好きにさせてはいけない
He finally figured something out. You won't beat me, Gon!
結果を見れば ネテロ会長ですら　こいつを 御し切れなかったのだから この選挙で確実に…
The two boys are about to
undergo a new awakening.